<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>democracy on</title><link>https://mwalton.me/tags/democracy/</link><description>Recent content in democracy on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mwalton.me/tags/democracy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Democratic AI</title><link>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/ai-democracy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/ai-democracy/</guid><description>Papers [[notes/dem-ai|Democratising AI: Multiple Meanings, Goals, and Methods]]</description></item><item><title>Do Artifacts Have Politics?</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/artifact-politics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/artifact-politics/</guid><description>machines, structures &amp;amp; systems analyzed the ways in which they embody forms of power and authority authoritarian technologies: system-centered, powerful, unstable democratic technologies: human-centered, weak, resourceful &amp;amp; durable Environmentalist Denis Hayes&amp;rsquo; example: dispersed solar more compatible w/ social equity, freedom &amp;amp; cultural pluralism vs nuclear power Scarcely a new invention comes along that someone does not proclaim it the salvation of a free society</description></item><item><title>Democratising AI: Multiple Meanings, Goals and Methods</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/dem-ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/dem-ai/</guid><description>Democratising AI: Multiple Meanings, Goals, and Methods Defines four modalities of &amp;ldquo;democratization&amp;rdquo;: Use: reducing the costs of acquiring and running AI tools providing intuitive interfaces to facilitate human-AI interaction w/o extensive training or technical skills Development: model, code &amp;amp; data sharing compute access project support &amp;amp; coordination education &amp;amp; upskilling Profits: avoid widening socioeconomic divide between leading &amp;amp; lagging nations ease financial burden of job loss to automation Governance: decisions on usage, development and profit reflect interests and preferences of impacted peoples decentralizing control away from big tech normative cross-cultural questions ensuring benefits and burdens distributed fairly May conflict (eg governance may restrict use or governance) democratization =/= dissemination positive value of AI democratization rooted in how well the effort reflects interests and values of impacted stakeholders</description></item><item><title>Liquid Democracy: Two Experiments on Delegation in Voting</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/lqdem-2exps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/lqdem-2exps/</guid><description>paper
primary concern: are experts correctly identified? common interests model: voters receive independent signals; ex ante equal prob one of two values common objective: identify state correctly via majority vote signal precision (probability of correctness) varies across individuals experts publicly identified, precision of their signals public info voter precision private info, weakly lower than experts if voter delegates, vote is randomly assigned to one of the experts (weird) theoretical results equilibrium w/ positive delegation that dominates majority voting w/o delegation.</description></item><item><title>💊 Decidim (metagov seminar)</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/mg-sem-decim/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/mg-sem-decim/</guid><description>Background why digital tools for democracy need to be developed democratically decidim.org decidim github decidim social contract Meeting Notes speaker: Arnau Montarde free, open source democratic platform in Barcelona for citizen participation context: why decidim?</description></item><item><title>Democracy</title><link>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/democracy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/democracy/</guid><description>Democratic Innovation Concepts [[thoughts/deliberation|Deliberative Polling]] Citizens&amp;rsquo; assemblies Sortitinos Policy Juries Citizens’ Initiative Review [[thoughts/liquid-democracy|Liquid Democracy]]</description></item><item><title>Participatory AI</title><link>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/participatory-ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/participatory-ai/</guid><description>Participatory design (PD) is the active involvement of users in the design of some system, product or process. It is a [[thoughts/democracy|democratic]] approach to designing social and technological systems that involve interaction with humans.</description></item></channel></rss>