<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>democracy on</title><link>https://mwalton.me/tags/democracy/</link><description>Recent content in democracy on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mwalton.me/tags/democracy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Do Artifacts Have Politics?</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/artifact-politics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/artifact-politics/</guid><description>machines, structures &amp;amp; systems analyzed the ways in which they embody forms of power and authority authoritarian technologies: system-centered, powerful, unstable democratic technologies: human-centered, weak, resourceful &amp;amp; durable Environmentalist Denis Hayes&amp;rsquo; example: dispersed solar more compatible w/ social equity, freedom &amp;amp; cultural pluralism vs nuclear power Scarcely a new invention comes along that someone does not proclaim it the salvation of a free society</description></item><item><title>Liquid Democracy: Two Experiments on Delegation in Voting</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/lqdem-2exps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/lqdem-2exps/</guid><description>paper
primary concern: are experts correctly identified? common interests model: voters receive independent signals; ex ante equal prob one of two values common objective: identify state correctly via majority vote signal precision (probability of correctness) varies across individuals experts publicly identified, precision of their signals public info voter precision private info, weakly lower than experts if voter delegates, vote is randomly assigned to one of the experts (weird) theoretical results equilibrium w/ positive delegation that dominates majority voting w/o delegation.</description></item><item><title>💊 Decidim (metagov seminar)</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/mg-sem-decim/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/mg-sem-decim/</guid><description>Background why digital tools for democracy need to be developed democratically decidim.org decidim github decidim social contract Meeting Notes speaker: Arnau Montarde free, open source democratic platform in Barcelona for citizen participation context: why decidim?</description></item><item><title>Democracy</title><link>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/democracy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/democracy/</guid><description>Liquid Democracy dynamic democracy generalizing both direct and representative dem voters may cast a vote (ala direct democracy) alternatively, can delegate votes (called proxies) to a representative proxy recipients may in turn delegate as well (called metadelegation) Idea: bellman delegation objective: model in which expertise and alignment are captured.</description></item><item><title>Participatory Design</title><link>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/participatory-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/participatory-design/</guid><description>Participatory design (PD) is the active involvement of users in the design of some system, product or process. It is a [[thoughts/democracy|democratic]] approach to designing social and technological systems that involve interaction with humans.</description></item></channel></rss>