<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>M. Walton on</title><link>https://mwalton.me/</link><description>Recent content in M. Walton on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://mwalton.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Eugenics and the Promise of Utopia through AGI</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/eugenics-utopia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/eugenics-utopia/</guid><description>Secure and Trustworthy Machine Learning Keynote
Various AGI definitions: sounds like an unscoped system w/ the apparent goal of trying to do everything for everyone under any environment why would you want to build something so poorly defined?</description></item><item><title>How Design is Governance (metagov seminar)</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/design-gov/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/design-gov/</guid><description>Amber Case presentation to Metagov Seminar How Design is Governance
pubs mentioned The coming age of calm technology Calm Technology Designing a sense of calm into our everyday technologies Design for a Better World Anarchist Cybernetics we encounter daily inconveniences that are result of design process decisions &amp;ldquo;A good tool is an invisible tool.</description></item><item><title>All Watched Over By Machines Of Loving Grace</title><link>https://mwalton.me/documents/all-watched-over/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/documents/all-watched-over/</guid><description>1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 I like to think (and the sooner the better!</description></item><item><title>Russell-Einstein Manifesto</title><link>https://mwalton.me/documents/russell-einstein/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/documents/russell-einstein/</guid><description>In the tragic situation which confronts humanity, we feel that scientists should assemble in conference to appraise the perils that have arisen as a result of the development of weapons of mass destruction, and to discuss a resolution in the spirit of the appended draft.</description></item><item><title>The Values Encoded in Machine Learning Research</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/ml-value-encoding/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/ml-value-encoding/</guid><description>paper
calls into question vague definitions of ML as value-neutral annotation of papers to reveal &amp;ldquo;values&amp;rdquo;: justification for choice of project which attributes of project uplift / advertised consideration of potential negative consequences institutional affiliation &amp;amp; funding societal need: 15%, discuss negative potential: 1% 59 values codified most common: performance, generalization, quantitative evidence, efficiency, building on past work, novelty textual evidence demonstrating values reflect assumptions &amp;amp; implication supporting centralization of power contributions open source annotation scheme for studying values in documents apply to 100 influential ML papers textual analysis to understand operationalization of values quantitative analysis of affiliations &amp;amp; funding of influential papers justificatory chain: chain of reasoning for technical / societal need to motivate contribution !</description></item><item><title>Liquid Democracy: Two Experiments on Delegation in Voting</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/lqdem-2exps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/lqdem-2exps/</guid><description>paper
primary concern: are experts correctly identified? common interests model: voters receive independent signals; ex ante equal prob one of two values common objective: identify state correctly via majority vote signal precision (probability of correctness) varies across individuals experts publicly identified, precision of their signals public info voter precision private info, weakly lower than experts if voter delegates, vote is randomly assigned to one of the experts (weird) theoretical results equilibrium w/ positive delegation that dominates majority voting w/o delegation.</description></item><item><title>Federated Digital Gardens</title><link>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/fed-garden/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/fed-garden/</guid><description>Observations: federation is cool but: much of the fediverse consists of federated alternatives to centralized applications (mastadon v twitter, peertube v youtube, pixelfed v instagram).</description></item><item><title>💊 Decidim (metagov seminar)</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/mg-sem-decim/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/mg-sem-decim/</guid><description>Background why digital tools for democracy need to be developed democratically decidim.org decidim github decidim social contract Meeting Notes speaker: Arnau Montarde free, open source democratic platform in Barcelona for citizen participation context: why decidim?</description></item><item><title>Anticipatory Innovation Governance</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/innovation-gov/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/innovation-gov/</guid><description>Observatory of Public Sector Innovation: Anticipatory Innovation Governance
reactive governance approach is ineffective at handling rapidly evolving crises anticipatory innovation governance (AIG) aims to actively explore possible futures, experiment w/ policy to enact them and iteratively learn what to incorporate into a broader governance system not only create knowledge anticipating the future, but jointly shape and prepare for it, making dynamic adjustments along the way disruptive tech transforming production and distribution; changing status quo for economies and societies resulting in new inequalities future of employment skills income distribution trade wellbeing &amp;ldquo;action must start with the willingness to embrace radical uncertainty&amp;rdquo; collingride dilemma: trade off between clearly understanding the impact of a technology on society vs ease of influence over social, political and innovation trajectory when change is easy: need for it cannot be clearly foreseen when need for change is apparent: change becomes difficult, expensive and time consuming !</description></item><item><title>Get in touch!</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/contact/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/contact/</guid><description>If my research interests align with or complement your own drop me a line to discuss ideas and/or potential collaboration. Email below, I&amp;rsquo;m also fairly active on discord @mwalton</description></item><item><title>Random Ideas</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/ideas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/ideas/</guid><description>The compost heap of random scraps of ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about. Some are new, some are old; some are being actively thought about, others have been digesting for a long time.</description></item><item><title>Stochastic Parrots Day 🦜 (DAIR)</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/dair-stochastic-parrots/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/dair-stochastic-parrots/</guid><description>![[notes/images/stochastic-parrots.png]]
Retrospective Problem: presented as knowledge access systems; similar to issue w/ meta galactica for science Language: pairs of form and meaning, language models only have access to form Good at generating plausible sounding text; refined w/ preferences at producing non-offensive plausible sounding text Philosophers asking: “are the models thinking?</description></item><item><title>People + AI Research Symposium</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/PAIR/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/PAIR/</guid><description>Intentional ignorance is a value-laden choice, Margaret Mitchell
choice of dataset and curation define what is important model selection encodes additional bias generation of new data from users interacting with the model generates a bias feedback loop over and underrepresentation of subpopulations encode value judgements foresight is critical: intended use / users foreseeable use / users foreseeable discriminatory uses risks foreseeable harms foreseeable disproportionate harms &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m just an engineer / data scientist&amp;rdquo; is willful ignorance; inflicts foreseeable harm !</description></item><item><title>Microsolidarity</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/microsolidarity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/microsolidarity/</guid><description>Microsolidarity: community-building approach emphasizing meaning &amp;amp; belonging; highlights strives to identify scale-invariant / self-similar features of organizations. written by Loomio (democratic decision making tool for online communities) co-founder.</description></item><item><title>Nomadism</title><link>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/nomadism/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/nomadism/</guid><description>Transition Towns: a movement I first read about in [[books/pluriverse|Designs for the Pluriverse]]
{Third, maker, hacker}spaces The Commons, SF Noisebridge, SF Past Lives, PDX Hedron, PDX Coliving Networks I&amp;rsquo;m followed with some passing interest development and discourse around The Network Statesor various forms of coliving / cooperatives that blend virtual social spaces with physical environments.</description></item><item><title>Rebuilding Society on Meaning</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/meaning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/meaning/</guid><description>Rebuilding Society on Meaning
Ideas an interesting modeling approach could be combining an LM that converses with users encouraging them to introspect on their values combined w/ a theory of mind that the model constructs (and persists) of them between use sessions (this could also get quite dark) i like the idea of trying to align recommenders w/ what users actually value, however I&amp;rsquo;m concerned about how the existing incentive structure (advertising / attention economy / surveillance capitalism) will incorporate research in this area.</description></item><item><title># Hunting for naval mines with deep neural networks</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/mlo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/mlo/</guid><description>Daniel Gebhardt, Keyur Parikh, Iryna Dzieciuch, Michael Walton, Nhut Anh Vo Hoang
![[cv/pubs/images/mlo.png]]
Explosive naval mines pose a threat to ocean and sea faring vessels, both military and civilian.</description></item><item><title>Distributed Consensus Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/dac-rl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/dac-rl/</guid><description>Michael Walton, Benjamin Migliori, John Reeder ![[cv/pubs/images/dac.png]] A system is provided for performing a predetermined function within a total area of operation, wherein the system includes a plurality of autonomous agents.</description></item><item><title>Intention-based Behavioral Anomaly Detection</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/intent-anom/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/intent-anom/</guid><description>Fan Hung, Xu Xie, Andrew Fuchs, Michael Walton, Siyuan Qi, Yixin Zhu, Doug Lange, Song-Chun Zhu ![[cv/pubs/images/intent-anom.png]] In this work we consider the problem of detecting anomalous deviations from expected behavioral trajectories generated by a multi-agent system.</description></item><item><title>Multi-agent Reinforcement Learning in OpenSpiel: A Reproduction Report</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/rl-openspiel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/rl-openspiel/</guid><description>paper, code
Michael Walton, Viliam Lisy ![[cv/pubs/images/rcfr_horz.png]] In this report, we present results reproductions for several core algorithms implemented in the OpenSpiel framework for learning in games.</description></item><item><title>Theory of Mind for Deep Reinforcement Learning in Hanabi</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/tom-rl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/tom-rl/</guid><description>Andrew Fuchs, Michael Walton, Theresa Chadwick, Doug Lange ![[cv/pubs/images/hanabi_horz.png]] The partially observable card game Hanabi has recently been proposed as a new AI challenge problem due to its dependence on implicit communication conventions and apparent necessity of theory of mind reasoning for efficient play.</description></item><item><title>Unsupervised anomaly detection for digital radio frequency transmissions</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/mdn-anom/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/mdn-anom/</guid><description>Michael Walton, Maurice Ayache, Logan Straatemeier, Daniel Gebhardt, Benjamin Migliori ![[cv/pubs/images/rf.png]]
We present a novel method of unsupervised anomaly detection using long-short-term memory mixture density networks (LSTM-MDN), applied to timeseries data of digital radio transmissions.</description></item><item><title>Alignment</title><link>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/alignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/alignment/</guid><description>🚧 TODO 🚧
Central themes [[thoughts/participatory-design]] [[thoughts/transparency]] [[thoughts/biomimicry]] Contestable AI contestable.ai Meaning Alignment there are some interesting emerging ideas around [[notes/meaning|meaning]] aligned machine learning; I&amp;rsquo;m cautiously optimistic on this direction depending on what organizations get involved coopts the concept</description></item><item><title>Animal Architects</title><link>https://mwalton.me/books/animal-architects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/books/animal-architects/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Biomimicry</title><link>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/biomimicry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/biomimicry/</guid><description>Biomimicry is basically taking a design challenge and then finding an ecosystem that&amp;rsquo;s already solved that challenge, and literally trying to emulate what you learn.</description></item><item><title>Braiding Sweetgrass</title><link>https://mwalton.me/books/braiding-sweetgrass/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/books/braiding-sweetgrass/</guid><description/></item><item><title>citizen-science</title><link>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/citizen-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/citizen-science/</guid><description>🚧 TODO 🚧
iNaturalist I&amp;rsquo;m always excited to find something new and curious I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen before, and adding new species to my observations recaptures the nostalgic magic of the Pokédex.</description></item><item><title>Collective Intelligence</title><link>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/ci/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/ci/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be attending SFI&amp;rsquo;s Collective Intelligence Symposium in June. Fellow attendees and presenters feel free to [[cv/contact|reach out]]!</description></item><item><title>Current Doings</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/doings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/doings/</guid><description>Research Autopoiesis: Musings on the study and [[thoughts/stewardship|stewardship]] of intelligent systems: artificial, natural, collective &amp;amp; complex.
Scaling [[thoughts/participatory-design|Participatory]] Artificial Intelligence</description></item><item><title>Democracy</title><link>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/democracy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/democracy/</guid><description>Liquid Democracy dynamic democracy generalizing both direct and representative dem voters may cast a vote (ala direct democracy) alternatively, can delegate votes (called proxies) to a representative proxy recipients may in turn delegate as well (called metadelegation) Idea: bellman delegation objective: model in which expertise and alignment are captured.</description></item><item><title>Designs for the Pluriverse</title><link>https://mwalton.me/books/pluriverse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/books/pluriverse/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Digital Garden</title><link>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/digital-garden/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/digital-garden/</guid><description>I was greatly inspired by Jacky Zhao&amp;rsquo;s approach to Networked Thought and decided to build my own garden using their excellent Quartz project.</description></item><item><title>Emergent Strategy</title><link>https://mwalton.me/books/emergent-strategy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/books/emergent-strategy/</guid><description>Emergent Strategy, Adrienne Maree Brown</description></item><item><title>Parable of the Sower</title><link>https://mwalton.me/books/parable-of-the-sower/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/books/parable-of-the-sower/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Participatory Design</title><link>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/participatory-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/participatory-design/</guid><description>Participatory design (PD) is the active involvement of users in the design of some system, product or process. It is a [[thoughts/democracy|democratic]] approach to designing social and technological systems that involve interaction with humans.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/projects/</guid><description>This is a list of notable projects and publications I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on. Find me on github or scholar for more!</description></item><item><title>Reading List</title><link>https://mwalton.me/books/_booklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/books/_booklist/</guid><description>Currently Reading Curius Recent Reads Emergent Strategy, Adrienne Maree Brown Lightly on the Land, Student Conservation Association Animal Architects, Carol Grant Gould &amp;amp; James L.</description></item><item><title>Stewardship</title><link>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/stewardship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/stewardship/</guid><description>In the physical world, there is a complex relationship between land development and land stewardship. Definitions vary (and often stewardship implys some form of development) but for our purposes we&amp;rsquo;ll follow the wikipedia-level defintion and refer to development as &amp;lsquo;changing landforms from a natural or semi-natural state for a purpose, such as agriculture or housing&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>The Dispossessed</title><link>https://mwalton.me/books/dispossessed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/books/dispossessed/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Transparancy</title><link>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/transparency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/transparency/</guid><description> Data Cards Playbook Reward Reports AIAAIC</description></item><item><title>Vision</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/vision/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/vision/</guid><description>Vibrant, thriving machine learning research and applications ecosystems where diverse pluralities of stakeholders collectively co-design, plan, build and share artificial intelligence tools that align with their values and sustainably meet humanity&amp;rsquo;s needs.</description></item><item><title>web3</title><link>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/web3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/thoughts/web3/</guid><description> web3 is going great My first impressions of web3, Moxie Marlinspike Virtual Violence, Kadallah Burrowes</description></item></channel></rss>