<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cvs on</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/</link><description>Recent content in Cvs on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mwalton.me/cv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title># Hunting for naval mines with deep neural networks</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/mlo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/mlo/</guid><description>Daniel Gebhardt, Keyur Parikh, Iryna Dzieciuch, Michael Walton, Nhut Anh Vo Hoang ![[cv/pubs/images/mlo.png]] Explosive naval mines pose a threat to ocean and sea faring vessels, both military and civilian.</description></item><item><title>Distributed Consensus Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/dac-rl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/dac-rl/</guid><description>Michael Walton, Benjamin Migliori, John Reeder ![[cv/pubs/images/dac.png]] A system is provided for performing a predetermined function within a total area of operation, wherein the system includes a plurality of autonomous agents.</description></item><item><title>Intention-based Behavioral Anomaly Detection</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/intent-anom/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/intent-anom/</guid><description>Fan Hung, Xu Xie, Andrew Fuchs, Michael Walton, Siyuan Qi, Yixin Zhu, Doug Lange, Song-Chun Zhu ![[cv/pubs/images/intent-anom.png]] In this work we consider the problem of detecting anomalous deviations from expected behavioral trajectories generated by a multi-agent system.</description></item><item><title>Multi-agent Reinforcement Learning in OpenSpiel: A Reproduction Report</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/rl-openspiel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/rl-openspiel/</guid><description>paper, code
Michael Walton, Viliam Lisy ![[cv/pubs/images/rcfr_horz.png]] In this report, we present results reproductions for several core algorithms implemented in the OpenSpiel framework for learning in games.</description></item><item><title>Theory of Mind for Deep Reinforcement Learning in Hanabi</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/tom-rl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/tom-rl/</guid><description>Andrew Fuchs, Michael Walton, Theresa Chadwick, Doug Lange ![[cv/pubs/images/hanabi_horz.png]] The partially observable card game Hanabi has recently been proposed as a new AI challenge problem due to its dependence on implicit communication conventions and apparent necessity of theory of mind reasoning for efficient play.</description></item><item><title>Unsupervised anomaly detection for digital radio frequency transmissions</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/mdn-anom/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/pubs/mdn-anom/</guid><description>Michael Walton, Maurice Ayache, Logan Straatemeier, Daniel Gebhardt, Benjamin Migliori ![[cv/pubs/images/rf.png]] We present a novel method of unsupervised anomaly detection using long-short-term memory mixture density networks (LSTM-MDN), applied to timeseries data of digital radio transmissions.</description></item><item><title>Current Doings</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/doings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/doings/</guid><description>Research Autopoiesis: Playful musings on the study and [[thoughts/stewardship|stewardship]] of intelligent systems: artificial, natural, collective &amp;amp; complex.</description></item><item><title>Principles</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/principles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/principles/</guid><description>While on sabbatical I wrote alot of rants and manifestos (none of which I&amp;rsquo;d ever dream of publishing). I had plenty of critiques of the direction of the Artificial Intelligence™ industry, but it began to become clear just how directionless my own thinking had become.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://mwalton.me/cv/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/cv/projects/</guid><description>This is a list of notable projects and publications I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on. Find me on github or scholar for more!</description></item></channel></rss>