<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mwalton.me/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Study of 'Organizational Closure' and Autopoiesis</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/org-closure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/org-closure/</guid><description>Notes on A Study of “Organizational Closure” and Autopoiesis
cybernetics as study of systems open to energy, but closed to information and control aka &amp;lsquo;information-tightness&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Do Artifacts Have Politics?</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/artifact-politics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/artifact-politics/</guid><description>machines, structures &amp;amp; systems analyzed the ways in which they embody forms of power and authority authoritarian technologies: system-centered, powerful, unstable democratic technologies: human-centered, weak, resourceful &amp;amp; durable Environmentalist Denis Hayes&amp;rsquo; example: dispersed solar more compatible w/ social equity, freedom &amp;amp; cultural pluralism vs nuclear power Scarcely a new invention comes along that someone does not proclaim it the salvation of a free society</description></item><item><title>Eugenics and the Promise of Utopia through AGI</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/eugenics-utopia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/eugenics-utopia/</guid><description>Secure and Trustworthy Machine Learning Keynote
Various AGI definitions: sounds like an unscoped system w/ the apparent goal of trying to do everything for everyone under any environment why would you want to build something so poorly defined?</description></item><item><title>How Design is Governance (metagov seminar)</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/design-gov/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/design-gov/</guid><description>Amber Case presentation to Metagov Seminar How Design is Governance
pubs mentioned The coming age of calm technology Calm Technology Designing a sense of calm into our everyday technologies Design for a Better World Anarchist Cybernetics we encounter daily inconveniences that are result of design process decisions &amp;ldquo;A good tool is an invisible tool.</description></item><item><title>The Values Encoded in Machine Learning Research</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/ml-value-encoding/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/ml-value-encoding/</guid><description>paper
calls into question vague definitions of ML as value-neutral annotation of papers to reveal &amp;ldquo;values&amp;rdquo;: justification for choice of project which attributes of project uplift / advertised consideration of potential negative consequences institutional affiliation &amp;amp; funding societal need: 15%, discuss negative potential: 1% 59 values codified most common: performance, generalization, quantitative evidence, efficiency, building on past work, novelty textual evidence demonstrating values reflect assumptions &amp;amp; implication supporting centralization of power contributions open source annotation scheme for studying values in documents apply to 100 influential ML papers textual analysis to understand operationalization of values quantitative analysis of affiliations &amp;amp; funding of influential papers justificatory chain: chain of reasoning for technical / societal need to motivate contribution !</description></item><item><title>Liquid Democracy: Two Experiments on Delegation in Voting</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/lqdem-2exps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/lqdem-2exps/</guid><description>paper
primary concern: are experts correctly identified? common interests model: voters receive independent signals; ex ante equal prob one of two values common objective: identify state correctly via majority vote signal precision (probability of correctness) varies across individuals experts publicly identified, precision of their signals public info voter precision private info, weakly lower than experts if voter delegates, vote is randomly assigned to one of the experts (weird) theoretical results equilibrium w/ positive delegation that dominates majority voting w/o delegation.</description></item><item><title>💊 Decidim (metagov seminar)</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/mg-sem-decim/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/mg-sem-decim/</guid><description>Background why digital tools for democracy need to be developed democratically decidim.org decidim github decidim social contract Meeting Notes speaker: Arnau Montarde free, open source democratic platform in Barcelona for citizen participation context: why decidim?</description></item><item><title>Anticipatory Innovation Governance</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/innovation-gov/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/innovation-gov/</guid><description>Observatory of Public Sector Innovation: Anticipatory Innovation Governance
reactive governance approach is ineffective at handling rapidly evolving crises anticipatory innovation governance (AIG) aims to actively explore possible futures, experiment w/ policy to enact them and iteratively learn what to incorporate into a broader governance system not only create knowledge anticipating the future, but jointly shape and prepare for it, making dynamic adjustments along the way disruptive tech transforming production and distribution; changing status quo for economies and societies resulting in new inequalities future of employment skills income distribution trade wellbeing &amp;ldquo;action must start with the willingness to embrace radical uncertainty&amp;rdquo; collingride dilemma: trade off between clearly understanding the impact of a technology on society vs ease of influence over social, political and innovation trajectory when change is easy: need for it cannot be clearly foreseen when need for change is apparent: change becomes difficult, expensive and time consuming !</description></item><item><title>Stochastic Parrots Day 🦜 (DAIR)</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/dair-stochastic-parrots/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/dair-stochastic-parrots/</guid><description>![[notes/images/stochastic-parrots.png]]
Retrospective Problem: presented as knowledge access systems; similar to issue w/ meta galactica for science Language: pairs of form and meaning, language models only have access to form Good at generating plausible sounding text; refined w/ preferences at producing non-offensive plausible sounding text Philosophers asking: “are the models thinking?</description></item><item><title>People + AI Research Symposium</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/PAIR/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/PAIR/</guid><description>Intentional ignorance is a value-laden choice, Margaret Mitchell
choice of dataset and curation define what is important model selection encodes additional bias generation of new data from users interacting with the model generates a bias feedback loop over and underrepresentation of subpopulations encode value judgements foresight is critical: intended use / users foreseeable use / users foreseeable discriminatory uses risks foreseeable harms foreseeable disproportionate harms &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m just an engineer / data scientist&amp;rdquo; is willful ignorance; inflicts foreseeable harm !</description></item><item><title>Microsolidarity</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/microsolidarity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/microsolidarity/</guid><description>Microsolidarity: community-building approach emphasizing meaning &amp;amp; belonging; highlights strives to identify scale-invariant / self-similar features of organizations. written by Loomio (democratic decision making tool for online communities) co-founder.</description></item><item><title>Rebuilding Society on Meaning</title><link>https://mwalton.me/notes/meaning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mwalton.me/notes/meaning/</guid><description>Rebuilding Society on Meaning
Ideas an interesting modeling approach could be combining an LM that converses with users encouraging them to introspect on their values combined w/ a theory of mind that the model constructs (and persists) of them between use sessions (this could also get quite dark) i like the idea of trying to align recommenders w/ what users actually value, however I&amp;rsquo;m concerned about how the existing incentive structure (advertising / attention economy / surveillance capitalism) will incorporate research in this area.</description></item></channel></rss>